<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
 * See the NOTICE file distributed with this work for additional
 * information regarding copyright ownership.
 *
 * This is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it
 * under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as
 * published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2.1 of
 * the License, or (at your option) any later version.
 *
 * This software is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
 * but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
 * MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU
 * Lesser General Public License for more details.
 *
 * You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
 * License along with this software; if not, write to the Free
 * Software Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA
 * 02110-1301 USA, or see the FSF site: http://www.fsf.org.
-->

<xwikidoc version="1.2" reference="FarmTools.WebHome" locale="">
  <web>FarmTools</web>
  <name>WebHome</name>
  <language/>
  <defaultLanguage/>
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>xwiki:XWiki.Admin</creator>
  <creationDate>1425555202000</creationDate>
  <parent>Main.WebHome</parent>
  <author>xwiki:XWiki.Admin</author>
  <contentAuthor>xwiki:XWiki.Admin</contentAuthor>
  <date>1595846056000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1595846056000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.1</version>
  <title>Farm Tools</title>
  <comment/>
  <minorEdit>false</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>= Farm Tools =

This is a bundle of tools for XWiki farm administrator.
The bundle is actually composed of:

{{toc start="2"/}}

== Farm Importer ==

Ease importing a XAR package on multiple wikis.

Instructions:

* Attach the desired .xar to the [[FarmImporter]] page
* Autocomplete will help you while you type in the xar input of the form
* You can start the xar import on the selected batch of wikis by pressing the 'Start' button. You can also cancel the operation on the upcoming wikis by pressing the 'Cancel' button

== Farm Property Updater ==

Batch property updater for objects in multiple wikis.
It is currently made of the following tools:

* [[Farm Field Value Updater&gt;&gt;FarmFieldValueUpdater]]
* [[Farm Preferences Updater&gt;&gt;FarmPreferencesUpdater]]
* [[Farm field value updater - Copy from another document&gt;&gt;FarmFieldValueCopier]]
* [[Farm page objects deleter&gt;&gt;FarmPageObjectsDeleter]]

The first 3 tools allow to change the value of a given object property from one value to another. You select the name of the document containing the object to change (without wiki prefix), and the same document in all wikis will get its object property updated. The object selected is always the first object matching the object class to be updated.

In the Farm Field Value Updater, you can freely choose the object class you want to update, and you can set a constant value to one of its properties.

In "copy from another document" flavour of this tool, the value to set can it be fetched from a source document instead of being a constant value. The source document can be variable (resolved on each subwiki on which the action is executed) or it can be a fixed document, the same one for all subwikis. This allows to easier deploy a value that is already set on one wiki on the whole farm.

In the Farm Preferences Updater, the object is always of class 'XWiki.XWikiPreferences', so only properties of this class could be updated. The update is done using a regex and a replacement value, so you have the ability to manipulate the existing value to produce the new one.
Additionnaly, in this second tool, there is a special property named "doc.parent", which allows you to update the parent of any choosen document using the same regex mechanism.

The last tool, the page objects deleter, allows to delete objects from the same page on all subwikis, which can either be filtered by the value of a field (and delete only those that match) or not (in which case all objects of that class will be set).

* [[Farm Objects Checker&gt;&gt;FarmObjectsChecker]]

This tools allows to fetch a status of objects of a given type on a given document on all the wikis of the farm. It does not make any modification, is only to consult the state of the objects on wikis. Can be used to check rights objects on all wikis of the farm or to check presence of tags or comments on a given document of the wiki, to validate that a document can be overwritten before using the importer, for example.

* [[Farm Rights Add&gt;&gt;doc:FarmRightsAdd]]

This tools allows to add rights objects to a wiki, a space or a page (if rights are to be added on the wiki, the document XWiki.XWikiPreferences needs to be set, if the rights are for the space, the WebPreferences page of the space needs to be set). Users, groups, levels and the allow state can be set for the rights objects. This tool does not allow to update objects but only add new ones.

== Farm Class Manager ==

Mass update a class on multiple wikis.
[[Farm Class Manager&gt;&gt;ClassManagerWikis]]

== Farm Pages Deleter ==

Delete a set of pages from multiple wikis.
[[Farm Pages Deleter&gt;&gt;FarmPagesDeleter]]

</content>
</xwikidoc>
